jobs.com 2018-12-21

# Monster Privacy Center | Monster.com

**Your Privacy Rights - Monster Privacy Policy Highlights  
**

We encourage you to review our [full Privacy Policy](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx) for detailed information on our privacy practices.

Monster collects information about you and uses this information to help you connect with employers and job seekers and to provide other services to you. This privacy policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, shared, and secured, as well as your choices regarding use, access, and correction of your personal information.

## Scope of this Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to information we collect or use on sites and applications owned or controlled by Monster Worldwide, Inc. or its affiliated companies("Monster").

## Information We Collect

| 

---|---  
  
We collect information about you when you use Monster. We collect information directly from you such as your contact information, resume, and profile information. We also collect information about you automatically such as how you use and interact with Monster, your demographic information, and information about your computer or mobile device.

We may collect or use information about you from publicly-available websites whether or not you have an account with us. You will have the opportunity to claim or request removal of the information. However we cannot guarantee that we will not later collect from publicly-available websites other information that pertains to you.

We may also acquire information about you from third parties to further personalize and enhance your experience.

## How We Use Information

We use the information we collect about you to deliver the products and services we offer, respond to you, and operate and improve our sites and applications. Our services include showing you personalized content and advertising on Monster or other sites with which we have a business relationship. We may use your information to contact you about Monster updates, conduct surveys, or to provide informational and service-related communications, including important security updates.

Information you share in public areas of Monster or make visible in the resume and profile database may be accessed, used, and stored by others around the world. We strive to provide a safe environment by attempting to limit access to our database to legitimate users, but we cannot guarantee that unauthorized parties will not gain access. We also cannot control how authorized users store or transfer information you give to us, so you should not post sensitive information to Monster.

## How We Share Information

We do not share contact information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

If you apply to a job, provide your contact information to show interest in a job, or reply to a message from an employer, we share your information with employer and who may use your data and contact you for employment related purposes.

We share your information with third parties who help us deliver our products and services to you. These third parties may not use your information for any other purpose.

We may share information with third parties if you consent. For example, we may use your information to contact you about products or services available from Monster or our affiliates. If you opt in, we may supply your information to third parties who may contact you about their products or services. You may change your contact preferences by adjusting your [notification settings](http://my.monster.com/Profile/NotificationSettings).

We may disclose to third parties information that we have collected from other websites.

We disclose information where legally required.

We may disclose and transfer information to a third party who acquires any or all of Monster's business units.

## Access to Your Personal Information

We store your information to make your interaction with Monster more efficient, practical, and relevant. You may access, review, correct, update, or delete your resume or profile any time by [signing in to your account](https://login.monster.com/). If you do not have an account, or if you believe that someone else has provided us with your contact information, please [contact us](http://my.monster.com/privacy/EmailForm.aspx).

When you delete your personal information, we will retain logs and non-personal information about your activity on Monster. We will also retain an archival copy of your non-personal information for our business's audit and record purposes, and which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet. If your personal information was previously accessed by others using Monster, we are unable to delete the information from their systems.

## Other Information

Monster is not intended for children under 13 years of age.

We participate in the EU-U.S. and Swiss-US Privacy Shield framework, as described in more detail in the full Monster privacy policy.

We use cookies to help personalize and maximize your online experience on Monster. You may [turn off cookies](http://inside.monster.com/cookie-info/inside2.aspx); however, this may limit your use of certain features or functions on our sites and applications.

For information on how to protect yourself online, visit the [Security Center](http://inside.monster.com/security-center/home.aspx).

## Mobile Applications

Monster offers several mobile applications, including the Monster app and the Jobr app. Monster collects and uses information about you as described in the [full Monster privacy policy](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx), including any sections specific to each app.

## Contact Information

You may [contact us online](http://my.monster.com/privacy/EmailForm.aspx) for questions or concerns about our privacy practices or our Privacy Shield participation. You may also write to us at:

Privacy Office  
Monster Worldwide, Inc.  
133 Boston Post Road  
Weston, MA 02493

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland have the right to lodge a complaint with the Supervisory Authority for data protection in their country, should they find that we did not appropriately address their question or concern.

Our Data Protection Officer can be reached at:

Data Protection Officer  
Monster Worldwide CZ,  
Rohanské nábřeží 670/19, 186 00 Prague 8  
Czech Republic.
